The legend comes to life.
Les Misérables is a crime, drama, history film directed by Bille August.
In 19th century France, Jean Valjean, a man imprisoned for stealing
bread, must flee a relentless policeman named Javert.
The pursuit consumes both men's lives, and soon Valjean finds himself
in the midst of the student revolutions in France.
Jean Valjean, played by Liam Neeson.
Javert, played by Geoffrey Rush.
Fantine, played by Uma Thurman.
Cosette, played by Claire Danes.
Marius, played by Hans Matheson.
Bishop, played by Peter Vaughan.
Les Misérables is a 1998 film adaptation of Victor Hugo's 1862
novel of the same name, directed by Bille August.
It stars Liam Neeson, Geoffrey Rush, Uma Thurman, and Claire Danes.
As in the original novel, the storyline follows the adult life of Jean Valjean (Liam
Neeson), an ex-convict pursued by police inspector Javert (Rush).
It was filmed at Barrandov Studios in Prague, Czech Republic.
The film was produced by Columbia Pictures and Mandalay Entertainment and distributed by Sony Pictures
Releasing in the United States and by Entertainment Film Distributors in the United Kingdom.
The film explores themes of prisoner, paris, france, based on
novel or book, falsely accused, blackmail.
The tone is emotional.